<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outreachy on Ankita Sharma</title>
    <link>https://ankitaS11.github.io/categories/outreachy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outreachy on Ankita Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankitaS11.github.io/categories/outreachy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Outreachy | Week-2</title>
      <link>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/outreachy-week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/outreachy-week-2/</guid>
      <description>This is my second blog, in the Outreachy series, where I talk about my experience working with the Moja Global community, and what I learnt - dos and don&amp;rsquo;ts, probably?
It’s too early, to be honest, to comment on what one should not do, but I’m sure I’ve learnt what can be done to be better in the tasks you’ve been assigned to. A few points:
Discuss your questions publicly! Open discussions, issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB vs CosmosDB</title>
      <link>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/mongodb-vs-cosmosdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/mongodb-vs-cosmosdb/</guid>
      <description>As an outreachy intern at Moja Global, I was involved in discussions about storing data in CosmosDB and MongoDB.
This blog contains my notes on the comparison of MongoDB and CosmosDB. A lot of this is written in terms of how a database server can be useful for my work at Moja Global.
Factors affecting the choice  Better choice as document storage. Type of data that needs to be stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreachy | Introduce Yourself</title>
      <link>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/outreachy-introduce-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ankitaS11.github.io/posts/2022/06/outreachy-introduce-yourself/</guid>
      <description>This is my first blog in the series where I talk about my experience as an intern at Outreachy, and working with the Moja Global community! I&amp;rsquo;m more than excited to share how things go as i move along, and I hope to continue writing these blogs weekly.
In this blog, I will be talking about myself and the core values that helped me throughout the journey.
Who Am I?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
